Anil Niraula

3737 Legation St. NW, Apt. 105, Washington, D.C., 20015 Contacts: (202) 560-0918 / niraulaanil@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anil-niraula-603a0825/

Portfolio: https://aniraula.github.io

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Having more than 7 years of experience in full cycle data analysis that includes data collection, data analysis and automating data management workflows (ETL flow), as well as in statistical analysis, machine learning, econometric & actuarial modeling, package development, creating interactive apps.

Software skills: R, RStudio Cloud, MS Office, SQL, Git & GitHub.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Reason Foundation / Washington, DC

- Sr. Quantitative Policy Analyst

- Quantitative Policy Analyst

August 2021 - Present June 2016 - July 2021

- Developing internal <u>database app</u> (including R packages, SQL/R functions) to streamline data collection, analysis and management (ETL) workflow for the team
- Working with and developing <u>actuarial models</u> (R & Excel) and running specific forecasting scenarios for different state projects
- Developing and automating (with RMarkdown, Git, and SQL) large PPT presentations for stakeholders, developing customized reports and interactive <u>applications</u> around pension policy

The Heritage Foundation / Washington, DC

- Intern at Center for Data Analysis

January 2016 - April 2016

- Collaborated on collecting, analyzing and reporting data on state employment by using statistical software
- Conducted statistical analysis using Synthetic Control Method to estimate long-term policy effects
- Performed literature reviews and co-authored blog posts on education, labor, tax and economic growth

International Monetary Fund / Washington, DC

- Projects Officer July 2013 - July 2014

- Managed several projects on analyzing and forecasting economic and financial data using statistical software
- Conducted econometric modeling and data visualization, while generating and managing more than 8 databases
- Prepared economic reports, summaries and web-based materials for effective communication of project results

Exchange Data International / London, UK

- Researcher March 2012 - August 2012

- Collected, cleaned and analyzed macroeconomic data on majority of Sub-Saharan African countries in a team
- Generated, formatted and managed more than 30 internal data sets, while also conducting post-updates

Consulting Company Moscow / Moscow, Russia

- Financial Consultant November 2008 - July 2010

- Daily analyzed financial markets' performance using fundamental and technical tools, while providing training
- Provided explicit financial and technical consulting to company clients and informally mentoring potential staff

EDUCATION

DataCamp / Online: <u>Data Scientist with R Track</u>
 Charles Koch Institute / Washington, DC: Professional Management Program

November 2021
May 2017

The Johns Hopkins University / Washington, DC: MS in Applied Economics

May 2016

o Teaching Assistantships: Financial Institutions, and Business Communication

• University of Edinburgh / Edinburgh, UK: MS in International Business and Emerging Markets November 2011

• Touro University / Moscow, Russia: BS in Business Management and Administration (GPA: 3.67) September 2008

QUALIFICATIONS / SKILLS

Advanced knowledge: R / Git / GitHub / PostgreSQL / Tableau / LaTeX / Asana / HTML / MS Office –(Word, Excel(Macros, Pivot tables, Stat. functions), SharePoint, VBA, PowerPoint, Outlook, Access)

Prof. courses:

MS Excel / SQL Server / Data for Social Good

Conferences:

rstudio::global 2021 / Why R? 2021 Conference / Data+Viz Hackathon (Tableau & IMF) / RStudio COnferens / 7th Municipal Finance Conference (Brookings) / 2018 Index of Economic Freedom (Heritage) 100 Years of CES Symposium (BLS)

Languages: Russian (native) / English (bilingual proficiency)